# Daniel Retamal /

Associate

Practice Area: Public and Regulatory Law

daniel.retamal@ocl.cl

Daniel has gained his experience in Public Law, with an emphasis on fishing and aquiculture regulation. He has been counsel in special proceedings under the General Fishing and Aquiculture Law, such as petitions for aquiculture concessions, relocation, registration in the National Fishing and Aquiculture Register of aquiculture projects on private land, the lease, purchase and sale of aquiculture concessions and their registration in the National Aquiculture Concessions Register. He has also been counsel in the defense against complaints of infringements of the General Fishing and Aquiculture Law and ancillary regulations as well as compliance matters.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

2017 - present / Ovalle Consejeros Legales

2012 - 2016 / Acuasesorías Ltda.

2010 - 2012 / National Fishing and Aquiculture Service

#### **EDUCATION**

B.A. in Legal and Social Sciences, graduating cum laude, Austral University. Admissions: 2009.

Environmental Studies and Sustainable Human Development Honors Program, Center for Environmental Studies, Austral University, 2005 – 2006.

#### **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE**

- Aid in the Economics Course, Austral University.
- Aid in the Economics of Regulation Course, Austral University.
- Aid in the Natural Resource Law Course, Austral University.

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish, English and Portuguese

## LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-retamal-calixto-52a76515/